uh today we will talk about uh five
levels of supply chain planning so what
happens generally as soon as on time Del
delivery goes down or inventory goes up
people generally start blaming or
something is wrong with planning it may
be true or it may not be but what we
need to understand what are the levels
of planning we are talking here uh
supply chain planning happens at
different levels and at different times
depending on the resource
and this is organized at five levels of
supply chain planning Horizons so what
are they so if you can see in this
picture uh you can see the
organizational breath on the on the y-
AIS and planning Horizon on the xaxis so
you think start from top down so the
first one is the profit plan which
happens on the early
basis followed by Sales inventory and
operations plan which happen on the
monthly basis and after that you should
have a master plan which should happen
on on a bu weekly basis and then you
should have a material plan it should be
on a weekly to daily basis and and a
factory plan so let's dive into each of
them one by
one so so profit plan which mostly
happens on the annual basis over the 12
months period and profit plan is mostly
a financial exercise where you talk
about what should be or anticipate as
search that what should be your receive
what should the new product you you you
will be launching what should be the
head count what is the cap capital
investment or facilities in most
businesses if you think about targets
like inventory they're measured against
what is the days on hand or stock turns
you have set up right therefore the
starting point is the profit plan for
most of the organization so what G comes
under below if you think about as a
monthly process which look into 12
months forecast as a horizon is a Sales
inventory and operations planning I mean
scup is in itself uh I people can write
books on it we cannot cover in this in
this short Vlog but what in
simplistically speaking saup is a cross
functional process is a planning process
designed to keep demand and Supply in
Balance but monitoring external Market
demands changes through the sales
department and communicating marketing
changes to the internal organization so
what what happened during that monthly
process it should provide you realistic
demand uh talking about production
capacities what should be your inventory
plan to meet your customer requirement
uh it is a cross functional process
marketing should be involve production
Finance folks and supply chain of course
uh it should be documented and it's
mostly required communication and
coordination in different departments so
it happens on a on a five step basis you
start with the data Gathering uh looking
at your sales history understand your
demand planning or demand forecast
taking your inputs from your sales and
marketing folks come up with the
unconstrained demand forecast which
feeds into your supply planning where
you look into what your supply plan
Supply constraints any delivery issues
capacity constraint Manning issues so on
so forth so by reconciling your
unconstant Demand with your with your
supply plans you should come up with
your integrated or consensus for cost
which should feed into your Regional uh
Executive review more to follow
hopefully so once you g through this s
process I think this fits into your
master production schedule and and I've
seen not many businesses carry that sort
of position I think for me I think it's
it's very important because Master
production schedule is the is the
process Supply planning process which
links between Market marketing and sales
and manufacturing operations and
Engineering functions right where
there's are three driving factors which
is what should be your manufacturing
activities purchasing activities and
Engineering related activities to have a
good MPS a solid stable MPS you need to
have accurate bombs and you to have the
the inventory accuracy so following that
I think we follow the the weekly or
daily uh mat planning process uh from
that you have different different uh
systems some people run weekly mrps some
people work on on a spreadsheet creating
production schedules uh your weekly
process also create your supply
schedules it could be done by by minmax
planning it could be done by reorder
point it could be done on on on a k
replenishment the point is there has to
be a some sort of planning process on a
weekly daily basis to understand
customer requirement and meets customer
requirement right the last but not least
a factory planning schedule and I think
we underestimate the the importance of
of the of the factory plan or line
scheduling generally people release the
MRP or work order on a shop floor and
let production guys piix it and I think
this is the owner where this is where
Supply CH guys should take ownership and
work with manufacturing guys and have a
proper Line schedule where they measure
work order on time to release and work
order on time to uh delivery which links
with the on time delivery to a customer
if manag by canman on minac system then
planners need to maintain inventory
levels to
trigger levels to maintain a minmax
stock and andalon quantities so if you
want to know more about this blog uh
about the five suppliance planning you
can click on my blog uh which you can
see on the card hopefully we will stay
in touch and uh more to follow if you
have any feedback please do leave at the
bottom of this video thank you very much
oh
[Music]